### Mitesh Sevani (MSc)

### Web Developer

London 07877569127 msevani@gmail.com www.miteshsevani.com

#### **Profile**

Six years experience in web development. A Masters degree with First class honours in E-Commerce with Online Databases. My experience and degree have given me a firm grounding in the core Internet technologies. I have the ability to work as an individual and as part of team. I am highly motivated, well organised and always looking to expand my skills.

### **Experience**

## ESI Media (Independent, Evening Standard and Homes and Property) Mid Level Front End Web Developer

#### **February 2016 to Present**

Working as a mid level front end developer and delivering a range of apps and features for our stake holders and clients. Worked mainly with HTML 5, CSS 3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, Drupal and some exposure to ReactJS.

The role has given me the opportunity to write up documentation for various parts of the website and allowed me to mentor and train new members of the team.

## The Engine Group (WCRS) - Web Developer December 2011 to February 2016

Working for a large digital marketing agency for a global client. Worked at Engine for four years, with many different front-end technologies such as HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, jQuery, LESS, SASS and Bootstrap. The role included working closely with the design team to build web sites from scratch and maintenance of existing projects.

My role here progressed to Mid Level Developer where my duties also included mentoring and training new and junior developers.

## Demo Media - Junior Web Developer May 2010 to July 2011

Working at a small business web agency allowed me to gain hands on experience in web development. Making practical use of Internet technologies and skills gained during my Masters such as PHP, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL database and Internet security. Clients varied from global banks (Deutsche Bank) to small enterprises giving me the chance to develop a range of websites with their own unique requirements. I was also involved in all stages of the lifecycle from requirements gathering to maintenance which allowed me to liaise directly with our clients and get an overall understanding of software engineering.

### Accenture Technology Solutions - Associate Software Engineer October 2007 to July 2008

Joined back at Accenture after graduation and was part of the AOL project. Working on a content management system, which involved scripting in TCL and database technologies.

### Accenture Technology Solutions - Intern Software Engineer July 2005 to July 2006

Completed one year internship at Accenture, which involved two different projects and various teams. After excellent feedback and review, I was offered a permanent role after graduation. Responsibilities included writing and executing test scripts. Working as part of a data migration team, which involved migrating data from a legacy system to a new system. Gained valuable skills and experience in Oracle and PL/SQL.

#### Education

### University of Westminster, London - September 2008 to September 2009 MSc (Hons) E-Commerce with Online Databases (Distinction)

#### **Core Modules**

Internet Information Management (X/HTML, XML, XSLT, CSS)
Database Systems (Oracle 10g)
Web Application Development (PHP, JavaScript, MySQL, Oracle)
Commercial Web Design (Flash, Action Script, Web Design Concepts)

#### **Dissertation** (Content Management System)

My MSc project involved developing a content management system for a voluntary organisation. The CMS allowed the non-technical staff to add, edit and delete content on the homepage of their website. Additional features included statistical analysis of the total attendance at their various branches across the UK and a discussion forum. The project has allowed me to further my knowledge and skills in web application development and design.

# City University, London - September 2003 to May 2007 BSc (Hons) Business Computing Systems (2:2)

#### **Core Modules**

Software Engineering Object Orientated Analysis and Design

Systems Architecture Advance Databases

Mathematics for Computing E-Commerce (PHP and MySQL)

Business Object Technology SAP

**IT Skills** 

Web HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, ¡Query, ReactJS (Basic level)

Development SASS, LESS, Bootstrap, PHP/MySQL, Drupal

Databases: Oracle, MySQL, SQL

Others: Git, Subversion (SVN), Bash Script

**Additional** Qualified Yoga Instructor

**Skills &** Disclosure and Barring Service (DBS)

Certificates

**Languages** Gujarati and Hindi

Extra Curricular Member of Hindu Swayamsevak Sangh (HSS UK) since the age of 7, which is one of the largest voluntary organisations in the world. Activities include exercise, games and education sessions. Taking regular sessions with all age groups provides me with leadership, communication and organisational skills. Regular attendance has given me team working skills as well as professional development. Involvement in planning, organising and participating in various charity events, both at local and national level.

Travel is one of my main hobbies and interests. I enjoy experiencing various cultures and people and always take the opportunity to travel.

Yoga is also one of my passions and I practice this regularly. I am a qualified Yoga teacher from S-VYASA University in Bangalore, India. I completed the one month Yoga Instructor Course in March 2014.

I taught Maths and Gujarati for 3 years on a voluntarily basis at GCSE level on weekends. This allowed me to gain valuable skills in communication, leadership, organisation and professional development.

**References** Available upon request